JAKARTA, INDONESIA
SEPTEMBER 24th, 2003
KEMENTERIAN KESEHATAN
REPUBLIK INDONESIA
THE LAST OF US
Morning.
- Do I look like I'm infected?
- Show us your arm.
Yeah, it's not getting any worse, is it?
If we're out in the open city,
why aren't we getting swarmed?
- Don't worry about that.
- Well, I'm gonna.
What was Marlene doing
with an infected kid?
I'm not infected.
She found me after I was bitten.
- And she didn't shoot you.
- Clearly not.
She locked me up
and had her guys test me every day
to see if I was getting sick.
Test you how?
- I have to pee.
- Test you, how?
They'd make me count to 10
and hold out my hand
and then keep it steady.
But, you know,
I think what really impressed them
was the fact that I didn't
turn into a fucking monster.
Now can I please?
Fine.
Back there. You can find a spot.
And here.
Tear out a few pages.
There's not gonna be
anything bad in here?
Just you.
Oh, funny.
Broken.
Maybe a hairline. It'll heal fast.
She made it through
the fuckin' night, Joel.
It doesn't matter.
It's gonna happen sooner or later.
All right?
We're still close to the wall.
We sneak her back into the QZ.
We find a different way
to get the battery.
This is our best shot.
We take her back to the QZ,
someone's gonna notice her arm,
they're gonna scan her,
then they'll kill her.
Well, better them then us.
You need to stop talkin' about this kid
like she's got some kinda life
in front of her.
You hungry?
You can share some of ours.
Thanks.
Marlene sent me with my own.
Is that chicken?
Yeah.
Marlene said they get it from smugglers.
Guess not you guys.
- Hey. Hey!
- Why--
why are you so important to Marlene?
And don't lie to me
or we'll take you back.
You take me back,
you don't get your battery.
You heard that?
Then you must've heard
that he wants to shoot you.
I'm gonna talk to you
like you're an adult.
Okay?
Joel and I aren't good people.
We're doin' this for us
because, apparently,
you're worth something.
But we don't know what you're worth
if we don't know what we have.
So answer my question.
She told me not to tell anybody,
and now I'm telling
the first people that I--
There's a Firefly base camp
somewhere out west,
with doctors.
They're working on a cure.
I've heard this before.
And whatever happened to me,
is the key to finding the vaccine.
That's what this is?
We've heard this a million times.
Vaccines, miracle cures.
None of it works.
- Ever.
- Fuck you, man. I didn't ask for this.
You and me both.
This isn't gonna end well, Tess.
We need to go back.
Let's just finish it.
It doesn't matter if she is
or she isn't what the Fireflies say.
If they believe that she is then,
we get what we want.
If she so much as twitches.
Don't.
Okay.
Okay?
Can I have a gun?
- Absolutely not.
- No.
Okay, Jesus. Fine. I'll have to throw
a fuckin' sandwich at them.
It's clear.
Yeah, looks different
in the daylight, huh?
We should get movin'.
It's like a fucked-up moon.
- Is this where they bombed?
- Yeah.
They hit most of the big cities like this.
They had to slow the spread somehow.
Worked here,
but it didn't in most places.
So, the State House is across there.
It's about a 10-minute walk
if you could go straight.
- So?
- Long way or short way?
I mean, it's the long way
or the "we're fuckin' dead" way.
Well, I vote long way
just based on that limited information.
We have to check it from the hotel first.
Okay.
Where the fuck are they already?
You'll know it when they're close.
I didn't know last time.
How did you get bit?
You know the old mall in the QZ?
The one that's sealed off
and boarded up,
and no one's supposed to go in, ever?
That one?
Whatever. I snuck in.
Wanted to see what it was like.
Didn't think there was
gonna be anything in there,
and then one just
came at me outta nowhere.
Thought I got away, but.
So it was just you in there, alone?
Yeah.
How old are you?
Fourteen.
Wow.
Well, I mean,
you got some balls on you, sister.
Thanks.
Nobody's gonna be comin' after you, right?
Like, Mom,
Dad,
boyfriend?
I'm an orphan,
and, no.
Everyone said the open city was crazy.
Like, swarms of Infected
running around everywhere.
Not exactly like that.
You know, people like to tell stories.
So, there aren't Super-Infected
that explode fungus spores on you?
Shit, I hope not.
Or ones with split-open heads
that see in the dark like bats?
What was that?
Let's keep movin'.
You've gotta be kidding me!
Ya ever stay in a place like this?
No, a little out of our league.
- How do you even know what this is?
- Have you heard of books?
Wait, are we going in there?
Yeah, we gotta get to the stairwell
on the other side.
Well, I don't know how to swim.
- Seriously?
- Do you think we have pools in the QZ?
No, smart ass.
I mean.
I don't know how I was supposed
to know that.
This is so gross.
Check it out!
Ding, ding.
Yes, sir. I would like your
finest suite, please.
Yes, ma'am.
Would you like me to take your luggage?
- Yes, ma'am. Right away, ma'am--
- You're a weird kid.
You're a weird kid.
Oh fuck!
Oh, my God.
Sorry.
- You okay?
- Yep. Fucking fabulous.
Fuck. Holy shit.
Come on, it wasn't that bad.
You try climbing ten fuckin' floors
with our knees.
See how ya feel.
Well, when the fuck did that happen?
Maybe that one.
No.
All right, well, I mean,
maybe I could climb up there,
work my way around,
and open it from the inside?
No, well, I'm the smallest,
so it'd be easier for me to get through.
But you die and we get nothing.
You stay.
Can you give me a hand?
You good up there?
Yeah, it's a bit of a mess,
so I'm gonna need a few minutes.
Nice knife.
- Where'd you learn to do that?
- The circus.
Where are you from?
Texas.
- What about Tess?
- Detroit. It's in Michigan.
I go to school. I know where Detroit is.
So, you two like a--
Pass.
- How'd you end up in Boston?
- Pass.
No more questions about me.
How long do Infected live?
I thought you went to school.
It's a really shitty one.
Well, some last about a month or two.
But there's others been walkin' around
'bout 20 years.
- Ever kill one?
- Yeah, I killed lots of 'em.
Was it hard?
Like, knowing they were people once?
Sometimes.
What about that guy last night?
You can put the gun down, Joel.
What now?
There's so many.
The last time we were here,
they were still deep inside the buildings.
Then I guess enough people came through
looking for the QZ,
they went inside seeking shelter,
and that's how they get more and more
of the city bit by bit, year after year.
They're connected.
More than you know.
The fungus also grows underground.
Long fibers like wires,
some of them stretching over a mile.
Now, you step on a patch
of cordyceps in one place,
and you can wake a dozen Infected
from somewhere else.
Now they know where you are,
now they come.
You're not immune from being ripped apart.
You understand?
It's important.
I'm tryin' to keep you alive.
So we're not goin' that way.
No.
What do we do then?
Short way?
Museum.
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
Well, there's a way
across from the top floor.
Well, then I guess it's fine.
- We used to take it all the time.
- Okay.
- Look, it was fine.
- Awesome.
It's bone dry.
It could mean they're
all finally dead in there.
Oh, man.
Marlene pack you one of these
- or just sandwiches?
- Yeah.
Okay, so, more ground rules.
We're gonna go slowly.
If we come up against anything,
you get behind us
and ya stay there, okay?
Yes.
I have a spare hand.
Congratulations.
THE BOSTONIAN MUSEUM WELCOME
EXIT
GIFT SHOP OPEN WELCOME
Yeah, cooked.
Finally, some fuckin' luck.
I guess we should've gone
this way in the first place.
Oh shit!
What the fuck did that?
Maybe,
maybe he was attacked outside,
and crawled through the doors.
The door was open.
Could've been him.
- I don't hear anything.
- Who would you hear?
Who would you hear?
Are you saying an Infected did that?
Because I've been attacked by one
and it wasn't like that.
Okay, from this point forward,
we are silent.
Not quiet. Silent.
- What--
- No. No questions. Just do it.
INDEPENDENCE HALL
They can't see, but they can hear.
Run!
Run, run!
- You all right?
- Twisted ankle, but, yeah.
You all right?
Well, I didn't shit my pants, so.
You fucking kidding me?
I mean, if it was gonna
happen to one of us.
Hey,
let's get the fuck outta here.
- Put this around your arm.
- Thanks.
- Over there?
- Yeah, I know. It looks scary.
That was scary. This is wood.
Just wait there. Give us a minute.
There's probably more ahead.
So, we'll deal with it then.
I got it. I got it.
What about the kid?
I mean, maybe the first bite didn't take,
- but what about the second?
- How 'bout you just take the good news?
Can you do that?
Like to think, for once,
maybe we could actually win?
Just go, go and watch her.
Is it everything you hoped for?
Jury's still out.
But, man, you can't deny that view.
C'mon, let's get there before it's dark.
Where the fuck are they?
Stay back.
Joel?
- What the fuck is going on?
- I don't know.
They went inside.
- Come on.
- Tess.
Come on!
Tess!
EXIT
Holy shit.
Jesus.
Okay.
I mean, there's gotta be
a fuckin' radio or somethin', right?
Who killed them? FEDRA?
No.
One of them got bit.
The healthy ones fought the sick ones.
Everyone lost.
Tess? What're you doin'?
Where did Marlene say
that she was taking you?
- Ellie!
- I don't know. Just west.
Just west. Fuck. Okay.
Well, I mean, one of them's gotta have
a map on them, right?
- Joel, can ya help me?
- No!
Tess, it's over.
- We are going home.
- That's not my fucking home!
I'm stayin'.
I mean, our luck had to run out
sooner or later.
Fuck.
She's infected.
Show me.
Joel.
Oops, right?
Take your bandage off.
Look.
Joel?
This is real.
Joel, she's fucking real.
I need you to get her
to Bill and Frank's.
- No.
- They'll take her off your hands.
- They'll handle it from here.
No, no, no, I can't. They won't take her.
- They're not gonna take her.
- They will 'cause you'll convince them.
Yes, you will.
I never ask you for anything,
- not to feel the way I felt.
- No.
Shut the fuck up 'cause I don't have time.
This is your chance.
You get her there,
you keep her alive,
and you set everything right.
All the shit we did.
Please say yes, Joel, please.
Oh fuck!
- How many?
- All of them.
Maybe a minute.
- What are you doing?
- Making sure that they don't follow you.
Joel.
Save who you can save.
No!
We're not leaving her!
Get off me, you fucker!
I'm not going with you!